<chapter id="chapter.gui.wizard">
  <title>Navigating the Wizard Window</title>
  <para>
    The Wizard window starts up automatically at the start of the Covered GUI.  It allows the user to quickly perform
    some of the more regular tasks within the GUI. The window is not necessary for performing these tasks, but for the
    new user it makes figuring out how to perform these tasks a bit easier.  <xref linkend="figure.gui.wizard"/> shows the
    layout of this window.
  </para>
  <para>
    <figure id="figure.gui.wizard">
      <title>Covered GUI Wizard Window</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/wizard.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </para>
  <para>
    The buttons at the top of the window are shortcuts to performing the tasks displayed on the button.  Clicking the
    associated button will cause a window to open to perform the given task.  The following are the available shortcut
    buttons:
  </para>
  <para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Generate New CDD File</emphasis></para>
        <para>
          Allows the user to create a new CDD file for a given design by specifying the various scoring options needed
          to create the CDD file.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Open/Merge CDD File(s)</emphasis></para>
        <para>
          Opens a CDD file for coverage viewing.  If one or more CDD files have previously been opened, this option
          opens and merges one or more CDD files with the coverage results of the previous CDD files for coverage viewing.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Rank CDD Files</emphasis></para>
        <para>
          Allows the user to specify CDD files that will be compared with one another and ranked in the order that they
          should be run in a regression to achieve the most coverage in the least amount of time.  It also indicates which
          CDD files do not add any interesting coverage information and could, therefore, be excluded from regression for
          the purposes of code coverage.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  <para>
    At the bottom of the wizard window, there is a checkbutton option that allows the user to not display the wizard
    window on startup.  This option can be changed in the <xref linkend="section.gui.pref.general"/> at any time.
  </para>
  <para>
    When the wizard window is closed, it can be redisplayed by clicking on the 
    <emphasis role="bold"><code>View > Wizard...</code></emphasis> menu item.  The window will automatically be closed when a button
    on the wizard window is clicked or when the user closes the window with the window manager's "X" button.
  </para>
  
</chapter>
