<chapter id="chapter.installation">
  <title>Installation</title>
  
  <sect1 id="section.installation.prereqs">
    <title>Prerequisites</title>
    <para>
      The goal of Covered was to create a tool that has very few requirements to allow it to be compiled and run on all 
      platforms. The following is a list of all utilities/resources required to compile Covered. However, Covered is 
      primarily developed on RedHat/Fedora Core Linux and Mac OS X and as such is primarily tested by the developers on these
      platforms.
    </para>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/software/gcc/">gcc</ulink> (Version 2.96 or higher)</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/software/flex/">flex</ulink> (Version 2.5.4 or higher)</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/software/bison/">bison</ulink> (Version 1.28 or higher)</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/software/make/">GNU make</ulink> (Version 3.27.1 or higher)</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/software/gperf/">GNU gperf</ulink> (Version 2.7.2 or higher)</para></listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            <ulink url="http://tcl.sourceforge.net/">Tcl/Tk</ulink> (Versions 8.4 or higher)
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem><para><ulink url="http://www.nemethi.de/">tablelist Tcl/Tk widget</ulink> (Version 4.9 or higher)</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
      Covered is primarily developed on Fedora Core but has been known to compile with both 32-bit and 64-bit compilers 
      that contain the general GNU library of tools. It has also been compiled and run on Cygwin and Mac OS X.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="section.installation.download">
    <title>Downloading source</title>
    <para>
      To download the source files in .tar.gz format, go to the following URL:
    </para>
    <para>
      <ulink url="http://covered.sourceforge.net/downloads/">http://covered.sourceforge.net/downloads/</ulink>
    </para>
    <para>
      Double-click on the .tar.gz version that you wish to install. The browser should immediately bring up a window asking 
      if you would like to save to disk or open immediately. Choose the "Save to Disk" option. Another window will pop up, 
      allowing you to choose the directory to store the tarball in. After selecting a directory, click the "Save" button. The 
      download utility will begin downloading the tarball to the selected directory.
    </para>
    <para>
      Once you have downloaded a tarball, enter the following to unzip and untar the package:
    </para>
    <para>
      <code>> gzip -dc <emphasis>tarball_filename</emphasis> | tar xvf -</code>
    </para>
    <para>
      This will create a directory called covered-<emphasis>version</emphasis>, where <emphasis>version</emphasis> will be of the
      form <emphasis>major version.minor version</emphasis> for stable releases or <emphasis>date</emphasis> for development
      releases.  Enter that directory to begin configuring, building and compiling Covered from source.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="section.installation.configuring">
    <title>Configuring the build</title>
    <para>
      At this point, you are ready to configure the build environment to create the executables, libraries and/or documentation 
      for Covered. However, before you configure the build environment, you will need to make a few decisions which will lead to 
      different options given to the configure script. These questions are the following:
    </para>
    <para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis role="underline">Do you need to debug Covered?  (for most users, the answer to this will be "no")</emphasis>
          </para>
          <para>
            If the answer to this question is yes, configure the build environment with the 
            <emphasis role="bold"><code>--enable-debug</code></emphasis> option to the configure script. Doing so will allow you to use the 
            global -D option and/or the -cli (<xref linkend="section.cli"/>) score command option for debugging; however, it will 
            also have the side effect of causing the score command to run noticably slower.  For normal usage of Covered, this 
            option should not be specified when configuring.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis role="underline">Do you want to profile Covered's internal functionality?  (for most users, the answer to this will be "no")</emphasis>
          </para>
          <para>
            If the answer to this question is yes, configure the build environment with the 
            <emphasis role="bold"><code>--enable-profiling</code></emphasis> option to the configure script. Doing so will allow you to use the 
            global -P option to generate an output file containing internal profiling information for the run command. See 
            <xref linkend="section.profiling"/> for more information on the -P option.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis role="underline">Will you being using Covered as a VPI module and, if so, what simulator(s) will you need VPI modules built for?</emphasis>
          </para>
          <para>
            If the answer to this question is yes and you need to build a VPI module for the Icarus Verilog simulation tool, simply add 
            <emphasis role="bold"><code>--with-iv</code></emphasis> on the configure command-line. If a VPI shared object module is needed for the 
            Cver simulator, simply add <emphasis role="bold"><code>--with-cver=<emphasis>cver_include_dir</emphasis></code></emphasis> on the 
            configure command line, where <emphasis>cver_include_dir</emphasis> specifies the directory that contains the vpi_user.h 
            file. If a VPI shared object module is needed for the VCS simulator, simply add 
            <emphasis role="bold"><code>--with-vcs=<emphasis>vcs_include_dir</emphasis></code></emphasis> on the configure command line, where 
            <emphasis>vcs_include_dir</emphasis> specifies the directory that contains the vpi_user.h file.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis role="underline">Do you want to use Covered's Tcl/Tk GUI for interactive coverage analysis or just the command-line created reports?</emphasis>
          </para>
          <para>
            If the answer to this question is yes and you have a Tcl/Tk distribution that the configure script cannot find (i.e., the 
            tcl-config and tk-config scripts exist in a non-standard directory location), please specify the 
            <emphasis role="bold"><code>--with-tcl-config=<emphasis>tcl-config_pathname</emphasis></code></emphasis> and 
            <emphasis role="bold"><code>--with-tk-config=<emphasis>tk-config_pathname</emphasis></code></emphasis> options to the configure script.  
            If the answer to this question is no, specify the <emphasis role="bold"><code>--with-tcltk=no</code></emphasis> option to the configure 
            script to cause the GUI to not be built.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
      Once you have determined which configuration options you need, simply enter the following command:
    </para>
    <para>
      <code>
      > ./configure <emphasis>options</emphasis>
      </code>
    </para>
    <para>
      This command will create the Makefiles/include files necessary for your machine to compile the source code correctly. If any errors are generated 
      during this command run, it is usually an indication that some program or library is missing from your computer that is necessary for Covered 
      to compile/run. Please install any missing programs/libraries and type this command again.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="section.installation.compandinstall">
    <title>Compiling and Installing</title>
    <para>
      If the configure script completes successfully, you may compile the source with the following command:
    </para>
    <para>
      <code>
      > make
      </code>
    </para>
    <para>
      This will begin the process of compiling/linking the source code for Covered. This stage may take a while. When the source files have been compiled, 
      the covered executable file will have been created. To install this executable in your <code>/usr/local/bin</code> directory, enter the following command:
    </para>
    <para>
      <code>
      > make install
      </code>
    </para>
    <para>
      This will install the covered executable and manpage help files. Once covered is installed, make sure that <code>/usr/local/bin</code> is 
      in your environment path. You are now ready to run Covered.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
</chapter>
