<chapter id="chapter.gui.assert.source">
  <title>Navigating the Assertion Source Code Window</title>
  <para>
    The Assertion Source Viewer window allows the user to see the source code for the current assertion in the 
    <link linkend="chapter.gui.assert">verbose assertion window</link>. To view this window, simply click the 
    <emphasis role="bold">Show Code</emphasis> button in the Verbose Assertion Coverage window. 
    <xref linkend="figure.gui.assert.source"/> shows a zero_one_hot OVL assertion code with syntax highlighting applied.
  </para>
  <para>
    <figure id="figure.gui.assert.source">
      <title>Assertion Source Viewer Window</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/assert_src.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </para>

  <sect1 id="section.gui.assert.source.navigate">
    <title>Navigating the Source Code</title>
    <para>
      The source code for the current assertion will be automatically displayed in the text viewer when the window is 
      created.  However, the source code will be displayed as it is found in the file system, without preprocessing 
      applied to it.  This means that included files will not be displayed in an in-lined fashion.  To view included 
      files, simply click on the included filename (it will be underlined).  This will cause the included file to replace 
      its includer in the text viewer.  An infinite number of includes may be traversed in this manner. To go back to the 
      file that included the current file, simply click on the <emphasis role="bold">Back</emphasis> button located in 
      the bottom left-hand corner of the window. This will cause the current source code to be replaced with its "parent" 
      source code.
    </para>
    <para>
      Note that the <emphasis role="bold">Back</emphasis> button will be disabled when the top-level assertion file is 
      currently displayed.
    </para>
    <para>
      To exit this window, simply click on <emphasis role="bold">Close</emphasis> button. To see this help page for the 
      assertion source code window, click on the help (?) button.
    </para>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
