<chapter id="chapter.gui.new">
  <title>Creating a New CDD</title>

  <para>
    Creating a new CDD file from the GUI can be accomplished by either clicking on the
    <emphasis role="bold">Generate New CDD File</emphasis> button in the Wizard window (see
    <xref linkend="chapter.gui.wizard"/> for more details on this window), by selecting the
    <code>File -> Generate -> New CDD...</code> menu option, or using the shortcut "Shift-Control-N".  This file creation
    "wizard" allows the user to create a new CDD file that can be opened/merged into the GUI for coverage analysis.  The
    methods that the CDD creation GUI allows for creating a new CDD file are quite flexible and are completely compatible
    with the command-line commands.
  </para>
  <para>
    The following subsections describe the various windows used to create a CDD.  Note that the CDD creation wizard
    uses several "pages" to describe the various options to set for creating a new CDD file, using
    <emphasis role="bold">Back</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> buttons on each page for navigation.
    Clicking on the <emphasis role="bold">Back</emphasis> button will not cause previously filled in pages to be
    reverted to their default values but rather will remain populated with the user's data. Similarly, if a page has been
    filled in with data and the <emphasis role="bold">Back</emphasis> button is clicked and then the
    <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button is clicked, the page contents are
    retained.  The only way to clear out fields is to click the <emphasis role="bold">Cancel</emphasis> button at the
    bottom of each page and startup the CDD creation wizard again.
  </para>
  <para>
    Clicking the <emphasis role="bold">Cancel</emphasis> button at any time will cause the CDD creation wizard to immediately
    exit.  Clicking on the help (?) button at any time will bring up the user documentation for
    the current page (context sensitive help).
  </para>

  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.select">
    <title>Navigating the New CDD Creation Option Selection Page</title>
    <para>
      Figure <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.select"/> shows the look of this page of the CDD creation wizard.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.select">
        <title>CDD Creation Option Selection Page</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_selection.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
    <para>
      The first page of the CDD creation window allows the user to select whether all options should be interactively
      selected within the GUI or if a file should be read in which contains command-line options to the score command
      to use.  If the latter is chosen, the contents of that file are read in and are populated in the GUI, but the
      CDD creation wizard will continue in the same fashion as the first option, allowing the user to change, remove or
      add to the options found in that file.
    </para>
    <para>
      If the <emphasis role="bold">Create CDD by interactively selecting options</emphasis> entry is currently selected
      and the user wishes to not use a command-line file to populate the rest of the CDD creation pages, simply click on
      the <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button at the bottom of the page to continue.  If the
      <emphasis role="bold">Create CDD by using option file</emphasis> entry is currently selected, the user must either
      type a valid filename or select one by clicking the <emphasis role="bold">Browse...</emphasis> button to the right
      of the file entry area and select a valid file. Once a valid filename is selected, the
      <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button will be enabled and the user may then click it to continue to the next
      page. Note that any filename can be selected (whether it's a valid command file or not).  Only valid score command
      options found in that file are used to populate the wizard entries. No error message will be displayed if the file
      does not contain this information.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.name">
    <title>Navigating the New CDD Creation CDD Name Page</title>
    <para>
      This page is used to specify the name of the output CDD file.  <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.name"/> shows
      the display of this page.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.name">
        <title>CDD Creation Output Name Page</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_name.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
    <para>
      The output CDD name must be specified and, as such, the <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button is disabled
      until a name is specified in the entry field.  Any filename is allowed.  If the user wishes to make use of a
      "Save As" style window for creating a filename, click the <emphasis role="bold">Browse...</emphasis> button and use
      the window for creating a filename. When the <emphasis role="bold">Save</emphasis> button is clicked, the specified
      filename is placed in the entry field and the <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button is enabled.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.type">
    <title>CDD Creation Type Page</title>
    <para>
      This page is used to specify what type of CDD file to create. The four types of CDD files that can be created are:
    </para>
    <para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            An unscored CDD file that was created by parsing the design. This CDD file can later be scored via a VCD or
            LXT2 dumpfile.
          </para>
          <para>
            This option can be chosen by selecting the <emphasis role="bold">Parse Design Only</emphasis> radiobutton.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            A scored CDD file created from the design and from a previously created VCD or LXT2 dumpfile.
          </para>
          <para>
            This option can be chosen by selecting the <emphasis role="bold">Dumpfile:</emphasis> option. If this option
            is chosen, a VCD or LXT2 dumpfile is required to be specified before the next option page can be used. Either
            specify this dumpfile name by typing in an existing dumpfile name in the entry field or use the
            <emphasis role="bold">Browse...</emphasis> button to select a dumpfile.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            An unscored CDD file, a top-level Verilog file containing a PLI call to run Covered in VPI mode, and a PLI
            tab file that can be used by some simulators for compilation purposes. See <xref linkend="section.start.vpi"/> for
            details on how to use these files for simulation/scoring purposes.
          </para>
          <para>
            This option can be chosen by selecting the <emphasis role="bold">VPI Module:</emphasis> radiobutton. If this
            option is chosen, the name specified will be the name of the module file created that is used to allow Covered
            to run in VPI mode within a simulation.  The basename of the module file will be used for the top-level module.
          </para>
          <para>
            In addition to providing a module name when this option is selected, the simulator type that will be used
            when scoring can be specified as well as the timescale information that can, optionally, be specified at the
            top of the generated module.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            An unscored CDD file and a top-level Verilog file containing the necessary $dumpfile/$dumpvars calls to score
            the design.  This module can be compiled as a top-level module along with the design to produce a VCD/LXT2
            dumpfile to be used for coverage scoring.  See <xref linkend="section.start.dump.selecting"/> for
            details on how to use these files for simulation/scoring purposes.
          </para>
          <para>
            This option can be chosen by selecting the <emphasis role="bold">Dumpvars Module:</emphasis> radiobutton. If this
            option is chosen, the name specified will be the name of the module file created (the basename will be the name
            of the module and the basename of the VCD/LXT2 dumpfile created from the simulation) that will contain the
            $dumpfile/$dumpvars calls needed to score the design.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
      The timescale specifiers will be enabled if either the "VPI Module" or "Dumpvars Module" buttons are selected.  Selecting
      the "Set Top Module Timescale" checkbutton will allow you to specify a timescale that will be added to the top of the
      VPI or dumpvars module file (setting the timescale in top-level modules is sometimes necessary for compilation purposes).
      If the checkbutton is not selected, no timescale information will be added to the generated top-level module file.
    </para>
    <para>
      Figure <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.type"/> displays the contents of this page. When all necessary fields have been
      specified, the <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button will be enabled and clicking it will lead to the next
      option page.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.type">
        <title>CDD Creation Type Page</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_type.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.options1">
    <title>CDD Creation Options1 Page</title>
    <para>
      This page is used to specify several options to Covered's score command. See figure
      <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.options1"/> for the layout of this window.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.options1">
        <title>CDD Creation Options1 Page</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_options.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
    <para>
      The following is a description about each of the CDD creation options available on this page.
    </para>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options1.general">
      <title>General Options</title>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Toplevel module name</emphasis></para>
            <para>Required? <emphasis>Yes</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              The name of the top-level module must be specified for a given design to be parsed and a CDD generated from
              that source.  Simply type in the name of the top-most module in the provided entry field.  Once a name
              is provided, the <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button will be enabled to allow traversal to the
              next option page.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Root pathname</emphasis></para>
            <para>Required? <emphasis>No</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              This entry field is an optional one to fill. This value is only necessary if the top-most module to be
              scored is not the top-most module of the simulator. If this is true, then the value that must be provided
              in the associated entry field must be the hierarchical reference to the module to be scored.
            </para>
            <para>
              An example of a valid root pathname would be something like:  <code>top.foo.bar.dut</code>
            </para>
            <para>
              See <xref linkend="section.score.t"/> for more information.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Delay Type</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              This value specifies which delay should be used when a delay type of #(delay_max:delay_typ:delay_min) is
              encountered in the scored design. If this type of delay specification is not encountered, there is no need
              to change this value in the GUI. If the delay specification is encountered in the design and this value has
              not been specified, the default of <emphasis>typ</emphasis> will be used. Otherwise, the user can specify
              which delay value should be chosen by changing the displayed type to either <emphasis>max</emphasis>,
              <emphasis>typ</emphasis>, or <emphasis>min</emphasis>.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Race Condition Action</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              After the design has been parsed and elaborated, Covered performs a static race condition check on the
              design to verify that no potential race conditions exist. If a race condition exists in the design, this
              would cause the coverage results to potentially be errant.
            </para>
            <para>
              This parameter allows the user to tell Covered what to do if a race condition is found in the design. The
              valid values are:
            </para>
            <para>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>Silent</emphasis></para>
                  <para>
                    Specifies that no output should be generated. Any blocks with race conditions existing within them
                    will be automatically removed from coverage consideration.
                  </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>Warning</emphasis></para>
                  <para>
                    Specifies that race condition should be output and those blocks containing the race condition will
                    be automatically removed from coverage consideration.
                  </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>Error</emphasis></para>
                  <para>
                    Causes Covered to display the race condition violations and stop scoring after all race condition
                    checking has occurred.
                  </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para><emphasis>Ignore</emphasis></para>
                  <para>
                    Causes Covered to skip race condition checking completely. This option can be used if the user is
                    confident that no real race conditions exist in the design but Covered's static race condition checker
                    is displaying potential problems. If no race conditions actually exist, ignoring race condition
                    checking results allows more of the design to be considered for coverage.
                  </para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Use embedded race condition pragmas</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              If this option is selected, a user-specified pragma ("racecheck" by default) is parsed and any potential
              race conditions found between the off/on pragma pair are ignored by the race condition checker.
            </para>
            <para>
              See <xref linkend="section.race.avoiding"/> for more details.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Default Verilog Generation</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              Covered's parser supports parsing for Verilog-1995, Verilog-2001 and SystemVerilog, defaulting its parser to
              support SystemVerilog. However, for older designs which may contain names that are keywords in the newer
              versions, it may be necessary to change the parser of Covered for the entire design. This option specifies
              the version of the parser which is used for the entire design.
            </para>
            <para>
              For information regarding the ability to specify a certain version of the parser for a specific module,
              see <xref linkend="section.gui.new.options2.modgen"/>.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Include OVL Assertions</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              If this option is selected, any OVL assertion modules found within the scored design will have assertion
              coverage information extracted from them.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options1.exclude">
      <title>Exclude Options</title>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Exclude Always Blocks</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              If this option is selected, all <code>always</code> code blocks will be excluded from coverage
              consideration.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Exclude Assign Blocks</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              If this option is selected, all <code>assign</code> code blocks will be excluded from coverage
              consideration.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Exclude Initial Blocks</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              If this option is selected, all <code>initial</code> code blocks will be excluded from coverage
              consideration.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Exclude Final Blocks</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              If this option is selected, all <code>final</code> code blocks will be excluded from coverage consideration.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Exclude Within Pragma</emphasis></para>
            <para>
              If this option is selected, all code blocks will be excluded between the exclusion off/on pragmas. The name
              of the exclusion pragma is defaulted to "coverage" but can be changed within the associated entry field.
            </para>
            <para>
              See <xref linkend="section.score.ep"/> for more information.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.options2">
    <title>CDD Creation Options2 Page</title>
    <para>
      The second CDD creation options page contains a listbox which will contain the various user-specified options
      that have been inserted via the <emphasis role="bold">Insert...</emphasis> menubutton. Any options that exist
      within this listbox can be edited by selecting the option and clicking on the
      <emphasis role="bold">Edit...</emphasis> button or deleted by clicking on the
      <emphasis role="bold">Delete</emphasis> button. Additionally, options may be reorganized within the listbox by
      simply clicking on an option and dragging it into the needed position. See figure
      <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.options2"/> for the layout of this option page.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.options2">
        <title>CDD Creation Options2 Page</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_options2.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
    <para>
      To add an option to the listbox, simply click on the <emphasis role="bold">Insert...</emphasis> menubutton which
      will display a list of options. Select one of these options to display a window where the contents of that option
      can be specified. Clicking the <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button in one of those windows will cause the
      option to be added to the option listbox. Clicking <emphasis role="bold">Cancel</emphasis> in one of those windows
      will cause the option to not be added to the listbox. Clicking help (?) will display
      context-sensitive help information to be displayed about the current window.
    </para>
    <para>
      Figure <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.options2.insmenu"/> shows the contents of the
      <emphasis role="bold">Insert...</emphasis> menubutton. The following sections describe each option and its
      corresponding entry window.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.options2.insmenu">
        <title>CDD Creation Insert Menubutton</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_insert_menu.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.source">
      <title>Source File...</title>
      <para>
        Selecting this insert option will cause an open file selector window to be displayed.  Use it to choose a single file
        that will be parsed as a library file (i.e., the -v option to most Verilog compilers).
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.libdir">
      <title>Library Directory...</title>
      <para>
        Selecting this insert option will cause an open directory selector window to be displayed.  Use it to choose a single
        directory that will be used as a library directory (i.e., the -y option to most Verilog compilers).
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.libext">
      <title>Library Extension(s)...</title>
      <para>
        Selecting this insert option will cause a window to be displayed that will allow the user to add library file
        extensions to the library file parser (i.e., the +libext+ option to most Verilog compilers).
        <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.options2.libext"/> is a display of this window.
      </para>
      <para>
        <figure id="figure.gui.new.options2.libext">
          <title>CDD Creation Library Extension Window</title>
          <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_lib_ext.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </para>
      <para>
        To add a new extension, select the <emphasis role="bold">Click to Add New Extension</emphasis> item in the extension
        box (selected by default), type in the name of the extension in the upper entry box and either hit the "Enter" key or
        click on the <emphasis role="bold">Update</emphasis> button. If an incorrect extension was input, you may edit it by
        clicking on the incorrect item in the extension listbox. This will cause the item to be listed in the upper entry box
        where it can be edited or removed. Click the <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button to accept the specified
        library extensions and add these to the main window listbox. Click the <emphasis role="bold">Cancel</emphasis> button
        to ignore the recent updates in this window.
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.incdir">
      <title>Include Directory...</title>
      <para>
        Selecting this insert option will cause an open directory selector window to be displayed. Use it to choose a single
        directory that will be used as an include directory (i.e., the +incdir+ option to most Verilog compilers).
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.define">
      <title>Define...</title>
      <para>
        Selecting this insert option will cause a window to be displayed that will allow the user to add a command-line
        variable definition to be added to the score command (i.e., the +define+ option to most Verilog compilers).
      </para>
      <para>
        <figure id="figure.gui.new.options2.define">
          <title>CDD Creation Define Window</title>
          <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_define.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </para>
      <para>
      To add a new define, enter the name of the definition variable in the entry box to the right of "Define name:".  If
      the variable does not require a value, simply click on the <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button to submit it
      to the main window option listbox.  If the variable requires a value, click on the <emphasis role="bold">=</emphasis>
      button, enter the value in the entry box to the left of that button, and click on the
      <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button. To abort the addition of the definition, simply click on the
      <emphasis role="bold">Cancel</emphasis> button.
      </para>
      <note>
      The <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> will only be enabled when the user has entered a value in the "Define name:"
      entry box.
      </note>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.param">
      <title>Parameter Override...</title>
      <para>
      Selecting this insert option will cause a window to be displayed that will allow the user to add a parameter overload
      option to the score command. Because Verilog "defparam" is not used by the Covered parser, this option is the only way to
      override parameter values.
      </para>
      <para>
        <figure id="figure.gui.new.options2.param">
          <title>CDD Creation Parameter Override Window</title>
          <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_parm_oride.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </para>
      <para>
      To add a new parameter override option, enter the full hierarchical path to the parameter to override in the left entry
      box and add the override value in the right entry box. See <xref linkend="section.score.param"/> for details on how to
      specify an override value. After both values have been input, click the <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button to
      add the parameter override option to the main window listbox. To abort the parameter override addition, click on the
      <emphasis role="bold">Cancel</emphasis> button.
      </para>
      <note>
      The <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button will only be enabled if both values are input in the entry boxes.
      </note>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.fsm">
      <title>FSM...</title>
      <para>
      Selecting this insert option will cause a window to be displayed that will allow the user to add an FSM input/output
      state on the score command line.  This option allows the user to specify the location of FSMs within the design without
      inlining this information with the use of pragmas for the purposes of gaining FSM coverage information.
      </para>
      <para>
        <figure id="figure.gui.new.options2.fsm">
          <title>CDD Creation FSM Specification Window</title>
          <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_fsm.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </para>
      <para>
      To add a new FSM option, enter the name of the module containing the FSM in the upper-left entry box, the description of
      the output state in the upper-right entry box (see <xref linkend="section.score.fsm"/> for information on properly
      specifying the output/input state information). If the input state is the same as the output state, simply click on the
      <emphasis role="bold">Input == Output</emphasis> button which will fill in the input state with the same value as the
      output state value.  If the input state differs from the output state, enter the input state in the lower-right entry
      box.  When all entry fields have been filled in, click on the <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button to add
      the FSM description to the main window listbox.  To abort the addition, click on the
      <emphasis role="bold">Cancel</emphasis> button.
      </para>
      <note>
      The <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button will only be enabled if all entry fields have been filled in.
      </note>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.modgen">
      <title>Module Generation...</title>
      <para>
      Selecting this insert option will cause a window to be displayed that will allow the user to specify a Verilog generation
      (Verilog 1995, Verilog 2001 or SystemVerilog) for a particular module. This generation value will override the universal
      generation value (see the "Default Verilog Generation" item in <xref linkend="section.gui.new.options1.general"/>) for the
      design.
      </para>
      <para>
        <figure id="figure.gui.new.options2.modgen">
          <title>CDD Creation Module Generation Window</title>
          <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_mod_gen.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </para>
      <para>
      To specify a Verilog generation to be used for a specific module, enter the name of the module in the left entry box and
      select one of the Verilog generations in the drop-down menu on the left. Once this information has been specified, click on
      the <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button to add this option to the main window listbox. To abort the module generation
      addition, click on the <emphasis role="bold">Cancel</emphasis> button.
      </para>
      <note>
      The <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button will only be enabled if a module name is specified in the left entry box.
      </note>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.modexcl">
      <title>Module Exclusion...</title>
      <para>
      Selecting this insert option will cause a window to be displayed that will allow the user to specify a module to exclude
      from parsing and coverage consideration. More information on the purpose for excluding modules is discussed in
      <xref linkend="section.score.t"></xref>.
      </para>
      <para>
        <figure id="figure.gui.new.options2.modexcl">
          <title>CDD Creation Module Exclusion Window</title>
          <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_mod_excl.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </para>
      <para>
      To specify a Verilog module to exclude from the score command parser, enter the name of the module in the entry box to
      exclude. Click on the <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button to add the module exclusion option to the main window
      listbox. Click on the <emphasis role="bold">Cancel</emphasis> button to abort the option addition.
      </para>
      <note>
      The <emphasis role="bold">OK</emphasis> button will only be enabled if a value is specified in the entry box.
      </note>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.cmdfile">
      <title>Command File...</title>
      <para>
      Selecting this insert option will cause an open file selector window to be displayed which will allow the user
      to find a file that contains Covered score command-line options within it. Select a file and click on the
      <emphasis role="bold">Open</emphasis> button to cause the selected file to be added to the main window listbox.
      Click on the <emphasis role="bold">Cancel</emphasis> button to abort this action.
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options2.notes">
      <title>Other Notes</title>
      <para>
      After all options have been specified, the <emphasis role="bold">Save Options to File...</emphasis> button can
      be clicked to cause all previously specified options to be saved to a file which can later be loaded by the new
      CDD creation window. Simply click the button and specify a filename to save the options under and click the
      <emphasis role="bold">Save</emphasis> button.
      </para>
      <para>
      When all options have been setup, click the <emphasis role="bold">Generate</emphasis> button to create the new CDD
      file. This button will advance to another page containing the output from Covered's score command.
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.output">
    <title>CDD Creation Output Pane</title>
    <para>
    The final pane in the CDD creation window wizard is the output window. After the <emphasis role="bold">Generate</emphasis>
    button is pressed, the user-supplied options are gathered and executed within a system shell and the output of that command
    is sent to this pane's textbox. If the score command run was a success, the
    <emphasis role="bold">Open/Merge the newly created CDD</emphasis> checkbutton will be enabled, allowing the user to
    open or merge the new CDD file into the GUI immediately.  To exit the CDD creation process, click on the
    <emphasis role="bold">Finish</emphasis> button.  If the score command failed for any reason, the user may click on the
    <emphasis role="bold">Back</emphasis> button to change the options specified to the score command or simply click the
    <emphasis role="bold">Finish</emphasis> button to exit the new CDD creation wizard.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.output">
	      <title>CDD Creation Output Window</title>
	      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_gen.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
  </sect1>


</chapter>
