<chapter id="chapter.gui.toggle">
  <title>Navigating the Toggle Coverage Window</title>
  <para>
    The verbose toggle window allows the user to see which bits for a given signal have toggled from a 0-&gt;1 or a
    1-&gt;0 during simulation. To display this window, simply click on a highlighted/underlined uncovered signal in the
    <link linkend="section.gui.main.viewer">file viewer</link> of the main window.  This will cause the verbose toggle viewer to be created
    for the specified signal as well as display a "--&gt;" symbol in the Coverage Viewer on the same line as the selected
    signal.  This symbol is simply meant to help the user identify in the Coverage Viewer which signal is currently
    displayed in the Toggle Viewer window.  <xref linkend="figure.gui.toggle"/> shows the Toggle Viewer loaded with a
    4-bit signal called "err_vec" in which bits 3:2 have successfully toggled from a 0-&gt;1.
  </para>
  <para>
    <figure id="figure.gui.toggle">
      <title>Verbose Toggle Window</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/toggle_full.gif" format="GIF"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </para>

  <sect1 id="section.gui.toggle.layout">
    <title>Understanding the Layout</title>
    <para>
      The bit vector displayed is a binary bit vector, each value (0 or 1) represents whether that bit in the signal
      either toggled (1) or did not toggle (0) during simulation.  There are two bit vectors displayed for the signal,
      the top vector shows the 0-&gt;1 toggle information while the bottom vector shows the 1-&gt;0 toggle information.
    </para>
    <para>
      The name of the signal along with its MSB:LSB information is displayed at the bottom of the window; however, if the
      mouse cursor is placed over a specific bit in the toggle box, the MSB:LSB will be changed to show the displayed
      bit, making it easy for the user to discern exactly which bit has toggled/not toggled.  If the width of the signal
      exceeds the given space for the toggle window, a scrollbar will be allowed to slide left and right to view the rest
      of the toggle information.
    </para>
    <para>
      To exit this window, simply click on <emphasis role="bold">Close</emphasis> button.  To see this help page from the
      toggle window, click on the help (?) button.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.gui.toggle.excl">
    <title>Excluding/Including a Signal for Toggle Coverage</title>
    <para>
      The user may exclude/include any uncovered signal in the design for toggle coverage by simply clicking on the
      <emphasis role="bold">Excluded</emphasis> checkbutton.  If this checkbutton is checked, the
      <link linkend="chapter.gui.exclude">exclusion reason popup window</link> will be displayed, allowing the user to
      specify a reason for excluding this signal from toggle coverage.  Once a reason has been specified, the summary
      coverage information will automatically be recalculated and redisplayed in the
      <link linkend="section.gui.main.listbox">listbox</link> and the background color of the underlined signal in the
      <link linkend="section.gui.main.viewer">file viewer</link> will change from the uncovered background color to the
      covered background color.  However, the signal will still remain underlined, allowing the user to see the verbose
      toggle coverage information, if necessary.  If the <emphasis role="bold">Excluded</emphasis> checkbutton is
      unchecked, the summary coverage information and background colors will be readjusted to include the coverage
      information for this signal.
    </para>
    <para>
      If the user excludes any signal for toggle coverage in the design, the <emphasis role="bold">Save CDD...</emphasis>
      option in the <link linkend="section.gui.main.filemenu">file</link> menu will be enabled.  This allows the user to save the
      excluded property either back to the CDD file (or to a newly named CDD file).  Doing so will allow the user to load
      the CDD file at a different time and retain the knowledge of which signals have been excluded/included for toggle
      coverage.  Additionally, if a saved CDD file with coverage exclusion is merged with another CDD file, the excluded
      signal information is preserved for the resulting merged CDD file.
    </para>
    <para>
      If a signal has been excluded from coverage and an exclusion reason was specified, you can view the reason for exclusion
      by right-click-and-holding on the <emphasis role="bold">Excluded</emphasis> checkbutton.  This will cause a tooltip-style
      window to be displayed specifying the reason for exclusion.  The background color of the tooltip will be the same color
      as the "covered" background color to help distinguish it from a normal tooltip.  To cause the exclusion reason tooltip
      to disappear, simply release the button.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.gui.toggle.display">
    <title>Displaying a New Signal for Toggle Coverage</title>
    <para>
      If the Verbose Toggle Coverage window is currently displayed with a signal, the user may select a new signal in the
      <link linkend="section.gui.main.viewer">file viewer</link> of the Main window.  When a new signal is selected, its value immediately
      replaces the currently selecting signal value.  This feature allows many different signals to be viewed one after
      the other without having to create/destroy a new window for each signal.
    </para>
    <para>
      The user may also see the previous or next uncovered signal in the main viewer by clicking either the left arrow
      button (for previous signal viewing) or the right arrow button (for next signal viewing).  Note that the left arrow
      button will be disabled if there is not a signal previous to the current signal in the given module and the right
      arrow button will be disabled if there is not a signal after the current signal in the given module.
    </para>
  </sect1>

</chapter>
