<chapter id="chapter.gui.intro">
  <title>Introduction to the GUI</title>
  <para>
    The Covered report viewer GUI allows a user to view the coverage results from one or more CDD (Covered Design Database) files that have been previously 
    generated using the Covered score and/or merge commands.  The advantages of using the GUI versus using an ASCII file to view coverage results are the 
    following:
  </para>
  <para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          View code that is covered/uncovered within the actual source file text (more context)
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Quickly see which modules/instances were uncovered for each coverage metric.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Ability to hide/unhide verbose information for uncovered code.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Quickly find expressions that caused combinational logic cases to be uncovered.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Allows user to focus on a particular expression/signal/module/instance that is uncovered.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Non-useful coverage cases can be interactively excluded/included and summary information automatically recalculated.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </para>
  <para>
    Because the nature of a GUI interface is much more interactive than a generated text file report, the Covered report viewer is meant to provide the user a 
    more in-depth look at the logic to identify the reasons for not achieving full coverage.  This is the ultimate goal of the GUI interface -- to be an 
    interactive tool for identifying and understanding why full code coverage was not achieved and how to write tests that will cover those areas.
  </para>
  <para>
    The GUI report viewer is invoked by specifying the <emphasis role="bold"><code>-view</code></emphasis> option to the Covered report command.  The 
    report viewer is part of the report command and is, therefore, not used to parse/score a design.  However, merging maytake place with the GUI as 
    multiple CDD files may be read, merged (assuming all of the CDD files came from the same DUT) and saved in CDD file format.
  </para>
  <para>
    The rest of the user manual pages describe the various widgets and windows of the GUI and their functionality.  Additionally, this user manual contains 
    information on how to get the most out of the Covered GUI report viewer.
  </para>
</chapter>