<chapter id="chapter.intro">
  <title>Introduction</title>

  <sect1 id="section.intro.covered">
    <title>What is Covered?</title>
    <para>
    Covered is a Verilog code coverage analysis tool that can be useful for determining how well a diagnostic 
    test suite is covering the design under test (DUT). It is command-line based with an optional Tcl/Tk GUI 
    report viewer, making it portable across almost all platforms.
    </para>
  </sect1>
	
  <sect1 id="section.intro.cc.cando">
    <title>What can code coverage do?</title>
    <para>
      Typically, in the design verification work flow, a design verification engineer will develop a self-checking 
      test suite to verify design elements/functions specified by a design's specification document. When the test 
      suite contains all of the tests required by the design specification, the test writer may ask:
    </para>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>"How much logic in the design is actually being exercised?"</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>"Does my test suite cover all of the DUT?"</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>"Am I done writing tests for the logic?"</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>"Do I have any redundant diagnostics in my test suite?"</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
      When the design verification gets to this point, it is often useful to get some metrics for determining logic 
      coverage. This is where a code coverage utility, such as Covered, is very useful.
    </para>
    <para>
      The metrics obtained by using a code coverage analysis tool can be very useful for determining the following 
      about a design and the test suite testing that design:
    </para>
    <para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem><para>Completeness of the test suite in terms of logic coverage.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Unexercised logic in the design (useful in helping to determine what types of tests need to be added to the test suite).</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Corner cases in design that are untestable.</para></listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.intro.cc.cantdo">
    <title>What can't code coverage do?</title>
    <para>
      It is important to note that any code coverage tool is only useful in indicating how much logic is being 
      covered by a test suite. It does not indicate that the covered logic works appropriately. This, of course, 
      can only be verified by the diagnostics themselves.
    </para>
    <para>
      Additionally, it is possible that two or more diagnostics can achieve the same coverage and yet be 
      functionally testing different characteristics of a design. Since the coverage metrics are not improved in 
      this case, one may conclude that the second test is unnecessary. This may or may not be true depending on 
      what is being tested; it is always up to the test writer to determine the necessity of a diagnostic. Using 
      the code coverage tool results as the sole means of making this determination is not recommended. Use common 
      sense in these areas.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.intro.cov.cando">
    <title>What does Covered do?</title>
    <para>
      Covered is a tool that uses your design files along with standard VCD or LXT2 dump files to analyze the code 
      coverage of the DUT. The code coverage information is stored in a special database file that can be retrieved 
      and "merged" with new coverage information to create a summed coverage total for several tests. After a database 
      file has been created, the user may generate various ASCII reports that summarize the coverage information or 
      run Covered's GUI to interactively analyze the coverage information. Additionally, multiple CDD files from the
      same design can be ranked for the purposes of running regressions and understanding which CDD files do not
      add coverage information and can be excluded from regressions runs, if needed.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.intro.cov.cantdo">
    <title>What does Covered NOT do?</title>
    <para>
      Though Covered does perform some resimulation of the design to derive line, combinational logic, memory, and 
      assertion coverage, Covered is NOT a full-fledged compiler/simulator and should not be used for such purposes. 
      Additionally, Covered is NOT a linting tool. Many syntax/semantic issues that are not allowed by the LRM are 
      allowed by Covered for purposes of making Covered's core more generic and/or simplistic. Please make sure that 
      your code is properly linted in your design flow using an appropriate tool.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="section.intro.cov.diff">
    <title>What makes Covered different?</title>
    <para>
      Most Verilog code coverage tools perform a pre-compilation procedure known as instrumenting. During this procedure, 
      the coverage tool will read in the DUT and generate its own version of the DUT with additional code added to aid 
      in calculating coverage after the simulation is complete. The benefits to this style are higher performance of the 
      coverage tool when it is run after the simulation. The drawbacks to this approach are that it slows down simulation 
      speed and a trust issue that the coverage tool did not alter your simulation model when it performed the 
      instrumentation.
    </para>
    <para>
      Covered, on the other hand, omits the instrumenting procedure all-together and only performs its analysis on a 
      pre-simulated design. This means that Covered cannot make a mistake to your simulation and the simulation is allowed 
      to run faster since there is no additional code that must be run to get coverage data. The drawback is that there is 
      some overhead in post-simulation for extracting coverage data but this is typically less than the simulation overhead 
      in the other method.
    </para>
    <para>
      Additionally, unlike all other commercial coverage tools, Covered is free! No license managers to invoke and maintain. 
      No licensing fees and negotiations. The only thing the developers of Covered want in return are bug reports and user 
      input (and perhaps a donation if you find the software useful and want to see its development continue). Isn't the 
      open source life grand?!
    </para>
  </sect1>

</chapter>
