<chapter id="chapter.merge">
  <title>The merge Command</title>
  
  <sect1 id="section.merge.using">
    <title>Usage</title>
    <para>
      The merge command is initiated with the following call:
    </para>
    <para>
      <code>covered merge [<emphasis>options</emphasis>] <emphasis>existing_CDD</emphasis> <emphasis>CDD_to_merge</emphasis>+</code>
    </para>
    <para>
      The <emphasis>existing_CDD</emphasis> specifier relates to any existing CDD. If the -o option is not specified (see 
      below for details), this file will be replaced with the merged CDD created by the merge. This is important to 
      remember since merging is an irreversible operation (apart from generating a brand-new CDD from the design and 
      dumpfile using the score command).
    </para>
    <para>
      The <emphasis>CDD_to_merge</emphasis> specifier relates to any existing CDD that is not the 
      <emphasis>existing_CDD</emphasis>. Though it is not illegal to merge the same CDD to itself, the result is the same 
      as the original CDD. Note that all files treated as <emphasis>CDD_to_merge</emphasis> are guaranteed not to be 
      modified by the merge command. These files are only read by Covered and then merged into the information contained 
      in the <emphasis>existing_CDD</emphasis>.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="section.merge.options">
    <title>Options</title>
    <para>
      <table id="table.merge.options">
        <title>Options to merge Command</title>
        <tgroup cols='2'>
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry>
                Option
              </entry>
              <entry>
                Description
              </entry>
            </row>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                -d <emphasis>directory</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                Directory to search for CDD files to include.  This option is used in conjunction with the -ext option 
                which specifies the file extension to use for determining which files in the directory are CDD files.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
                -ext <emphasis>extension</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                Used in conjunction with the -d option.  If no -ext options are specified on the command-line, the 
                default value of '.cdd' is used.  Note that a period (.) should be specified.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
                -f <emphasis>filename</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                Name of file containing additional arguments to parse. You may specify this option more than once on a 
                command-line.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
                -h
              </entry>
              <entry>
                Outputs usage information for the merge command.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
                -o <emphasis>filename</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                Name of CDD to write merged coverage information to (if not specified, the 
                <emphasis>existing_CDD</emphasis> is overwritten with merged CDD).
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
</chapter>
